<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hari Kathaa हरी कथा</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hari Kathaa हरी कथा</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 21:42:25 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DMC in Saharsa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/dmc_in_saharsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 21:42:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/dmc_in_saharsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a DMC in Saharsa, Bihar. During the train journey, Baba sat for sadhana in His compartment. A person by the name of Kapil Narayan Suhurta who was a politician and an accomplished writer in Hindi was sitting nearby, watching Baba curiously. He started talking to a Margii who was with Baba. The Margii told him that Baba is the founder of Ananda Marga.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kapil became curious and so asked Baba,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;What is your profession?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishwaroop by Baba</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/vishwaroop_by_baba/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 21:49:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/vishwaroop_by_baba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since childhood I had a strong desire to see Vishvarúpa, the Universal Form of God, because in the Mahábhárata Krsna showed Arjuna his universal form and I thought, &amp;ldquo;If Arjuna can see it then why not me?&amp;rdquo; Even before coming to the Márga I had this desire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So once during a darshan in 1968, Bábá called me to sit in front of him. He told me to be seated in lotus posture, keeping my spinal cord straight. He touched my ájiná cakra with his finger, and with his touch my whole body and mind became purified and started vibrating with spiritual current. &amp;ldquo;What do you see?,&amp;rdquo; Bábá asked me. &amp;ldquo;Bábá, I see you sitting on a golden lion. You are smiling.&amp;rdquo; Then He said, &amp;ldquo;Concentrate your mind on sahasrára cakra. What do you see?” &amp;ldquo;Baba, I see a golden effulgence.&amp;rdquo; He said, &amp;ldquo;Go deeper. Penetrate your mind and see each and every part of your body.&amp;rdquo; I started seeing Sadguru Ánandamúrti present in each and every molecule of my flesh in the affectionate and gracious pose of varábhaya mudra, with smiling and charming face. He was not there in a body made of flesh, blood, bones, etc, but in the divine form of effulgence. Then He ordered me to withdraw my mind from the flesh and to enter into and visualise each and every part of the bones of my body. I did accordingly and saw the same glittering, shining effulgent divine form. Then he ordered my mind to expand and see into all the solid factor of the universe. I visualised that vast solid factor with millions of planets, galaxies, nebulae and stars, as all the things were in my mind. In that state my mind soared into an&#xA;indescribable world of effulgence. I saw the whole universe. Bábá told me to concentrate on every molecule of the universe. I did. My mind could encompass the entire universe penetrate each and every molecule. Lord Anandamúrti was sitting everywhere in the gracious and effulgent form of varábhaya mudra with his ever-smiling face.&#xA;Then he ordered my mind to cross, penetrate, expand and see the liquid, luminous, aerial and etherial factors respectively. My mind visualized His divine form accordingly without any effort, merely by his grace and wish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
