<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal_experiences on Hari Katha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/personal_experiences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal_experiences on Hari Katha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 23:07:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/personal_experiences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experiences of Ramdas Pandit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/experiences_of_ramdas_pandit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 23:07:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/experiences_of_ramdas_pandit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;source&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All stories below are from personal texts from Shrii Ramdas Pandit, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In summer of year of 1968 Baba visited Delhi. Before morning General Darshan as routine we arranged visit for Purana Kila ( Old Fort ) as a part of morning walk.  Baba was accompanied with R.Prasad ( Collector Central Excise) , Mangal  Bihari (IAS officer Gov.of India) Dr. P.K.Kymal, Venu Gopalan ( Ass.Com. Finance), Ravindra Dutta&amp;hellip;.it was nice group of devoted Margis. We reached at the foot of Purana Kila by car and finally entered in gorgeous gate of Purana Kila.&#xA;It was pleasant atmosphere and Baba looked very very bright and satisfied. We reached at small open ground. Suddenly Baba stopped and looked at sky above him. He raised His right arm and pointed to various part of sky with His fore finger as if locating something in vast Universe.  Suddenly Baba became serious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiences of Vispute Family</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/vispute_family/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 23:08:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/vispute_family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;beginnings-with-my-father&#34;&gt;Beginnings with my father&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am Padmakar Laxman Vispute. My parents, my children and their children are all ananda margiis by Baba&amp;rsquo;s grace. The first margii in our family was my father Laxman Vispute. He hailed from Jalgaon in Maharashtra. My father in his teenage years was already a devotee. He used to say that he wants to become a sanyasii (monk). He didn&amp;rsquo;t want to marry. With his thirst he already had found a guru who was known as Tukdoji Maharaja. He spent some years with Tukdoji and was hoping to become a sansyasii under him. Tukdoji convinced my father, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t become a sanyasii, lead a married life. Do not worry, you will find a good guru in future and you will find God.&amp;rdquo; And his words came true! In some way Tukdoji Maharaja knew that my father will meet Baba.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
