<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Excerpt on Hari Katha</title>
    <link>https://harikatha.eu/tags/excerpt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Excerpt on Hari Katha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 17:14:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://harikatha.eu/tags/excerpt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moralists march ahead</title>
      <link>https://harikatha.eu/articles/moralists_march_ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 17:14:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://harikatha.eu/articles/moralists_march_ahead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a DMC in Dhurba, Ranchi on the  10th  November 1964. During  the  noon discourse of Bábá, He said, “A perpetual war  is  going  on between  the  demonic  and the righteous forces and  it will  continue.  Good and bad, moralists  and  immoralists cannot co-exist.  One will have to surrender  before he other.  There cannot be a truce  between&#xA;the two.  It is  the  desire of  Parama Puruśa that moralists should  dominate  the  society.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stories by Acarya Kamlakanta</title>
      <link>https://harikatha.eu/articles/stories_by_acarya_kamlakanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 23:11:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://harikatha.eu/articles/stories_by_acarya_kamlakanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;source&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Published in the 2001 yearly issue of &amp;ldquo;Jamalpur: The Birthplace of Shrii Shrii Anandamurtijii&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I got initiation in 1959. A few months later, I got an opportunity to accompany Baba on His evening walk. I had heard that Baba was an incarnation of Lord Shiva. I made up my mind to test Him. I had a question in my mind, which I did not reveal in words: &amp;ldquo;Baba, if you are really a Sadguru, be kind to let me have a glimpse of God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DMC in Saharsa</title>
      <link>https://harikatha.eu/articles/dmc_in_saharsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 21:42:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://harikatha.eu/articles/dmc_in_saharsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a DMC in Saharsa, Bihar. During the train journey, Baba sat for sadhana in His compartment. A person by the name of Kapil Narayan Suhurta who was a politician and an accomplished writer in Hindi was sitting nearby, watching Baba curiously. He started talking to a Margii who was with Baba. The Margii told him that Baba is the founder of Ananda Marga.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kapil became curious and so asked Baba,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;What is your profession?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
